Guide to the Stanford University, Department of Communication, Honors Theses
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University, Department of Communication, honors theses
1947-2002
SC4-3762
Stanford University. Department of Communication.
4 Linear feet (50 volumes in 8 boxes)
Honors theses written by undergraduate students in the Stanford University Department of Communication.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Materials were transferred to the Stanford University Archives by the Department of Communication, and from Hume Writing Center in 2011.
Information about Access
The collection is open for research; materials must be requested at least 48 hours in advance of intended use. No photocopies may be made.
Scope and Contents note
This collection consists of honors theses written by undergraduate students in the Stanford University Department of Communication.
Access Terms
Communications; Student papers.
Collection Contents
- Theses, 1947-1972
  - Abuzaakouk, A.R., The development and analysis of press regulation in Libya., September 1971 (Box 1)
  - Berry, Fred C. Jr., Accuracy of Local Newspaper Items., December 1966 (Box 1)
  - Breitrose, Henry, Abstracts of Literature on Communication Theory., 1961-1962 (Box 1)
  - Brill, David G., A Quantitative Determination of the Authorship of Report from Iron Mountain., August 1969 (Box 1)
  - Bruno, N.J., Army News Feature Service., April 1968 (Box 1)
  - Dyba, Evelyn J., Research and Producation Plans for a Television Program on the Subject of Neurologically Handicapped Children., August 1964 (Box 1)
  - Elian, Sabine Charlotte, A comparative study of Local Evening News televised on three Network affiliated San Francisco stations., June 1966 (Box 2)
  - Elliot, Corbin P., Development and Uses of Television By the U.S. Army., May 7, 1963 (Box 2)
  - Eu, Angela, Film: Description., 1964 (Box 2)
  - Fitch, Stuart G., Freedom of Information and of the Press as Developed Under the League of Nations and the United Nations., June 1948 (Box 2)
  - Froning, Diane, Television Scolaire., June 1964 (Box 2)
  - Greenberg, Lt. Bradley, Project: Prospectus., August 1962 (Box 2)
  - Gregg, Frank A., A War Without Censorship., December 1967 (Box 3)
  - Harris, Susan K., Standing Ground., July 1971 (Box 3)
  - Hix, Jane, Propaganda and the Boston Gazette 1764-1773., September 1947 (Box 3)
  - Jones, David B., "Live Bait"-- A Script for Cimarron Strip--C.B.S., June 1968 (Box 3)
  - Klitzman, Stephen, Monopoly and Diversification of Control in Mass Media. (Box 3)
  - Kumata, Hideya and Wolflinger, Raymond, The Effects of Mass Communication. [missing]
  - Low, John, "Top Thirty": A forty four minute Documentary program on how radio Station KYA views its listeners., August 14, 1966 (Box 4)
  - Main, Robert G. and Bentley, Robert D., A Comparative Study of Anti-Draft students and ROTC Cadets at Stanford., August 1968 (Box 4)
  - McGilvrey, Marjorie J., The Uses of Television in Education Around the World: A Sabbatical Project., 1974-1974 (Box 4)
  - Miller, Nancy, Six Scripts for Educational Television to introduce children, from about the age of ten up to Shakespearean and Tudor comedy., August 17, 1967 (Box 4)
  - Notz, William G., A Survey of Technical Communication Research., March 1964 (Box 5)
  - Obregon-Garces, Evaristo, Evolution of the Communication Satellite Concept 1959 to mid 1966., November 1966 (Box 5)
  - Ramos, Therona, The Impact of Urbanization on cCommunication Systems in Latin America., October 1967 (Box 5)
  - Sanders, James Eugene Jr., Preparing the graphics for a new educational Television Station for the Purpose of producing a favorable image among viewers., March 1965 (Box 5)
  - Scheffer, Richard, Along for the Ride., September 10, 1969 (Box 5)
  - Sosahr, Susan G., A survey and Analysis of Full-Page Magazine Advertising, 1915-1964., Spring 1965 (Box 5)
  - Sweers, Peter C. Jr., The Voice of Information and Education. [missing], March 1966
  - Thomas, Patricia J., Popular Magazine Coverage of Rock Music 1954-1969., 1970 (Box 6)
  - Tousley, Col. Pershing, The Lost H-Bomb--A News Dilemma., December 15, 1967 (Box 6)
  - Turner, Polly, A Short History of the Growth of the Counterpart Book., June 1969 (Box 6)
  - Wakerly, Kate, Feminist Critiques of Television Commericals: Voices of the women's liberation movement., March 1972 (Box 6)
  - Weller, S.W., A Study of the Requirements and Methods Used for Assuring Quality in Technical Writing., November 1968 (Box 6)
  - Williams, Brian K., The First Year of Canfield Press., August 1970 (Box 6)
- Theses, Accession ARCH-2011-152
  - Carney, Paul, Honesty and the computer interviewer: social desirability effects of input mode and gender of interviewer on a computer survey., 1996
  - DeHaro, Analisa, The linguistic intergroup bias: the attributional effects of using linguistic masking devices in an intergroup context., 1999 (Box 2)
  - Diogo, Ines, Framed: media coverage of presidential elections. A comparison between Le Monde and The New York Times., 1997 (Box 1)
  - Egusa, Melanie M., Exploring Nisei and Sansei responses to and intergenerational communication about the Japanese-American internment: a two-generational study., 2003 (Box 1)
  - Fandrich, Rena, Effects of film-mediated foul language., 1998 (Box 2)
  - Kelley, Judith, The media and human rights policy: policy makers' perception of the effects of human rights coverage., 1995 (Box 2)
  - Lee, Elissa, The influence of chain ownership on member newspapers: a case study on public journalism in the San Jose Mercury News., 1997 (Box 1)
  - McCreery, Kimberly, The role of the journalist in Presidential campaign coverage., 1993 (Box 1)
  - McGrady, Jennifer, A comparison of media coverage of elections in Ireland and the U.S.., 2002 (Box 1)
  - Morgan, Benjamin Jeremiah, Bearing witness to a communication catastrophe? A critical communincation and psychological perspective of AIDS/HIV prevention campaigns., 1994 (Box 2)
  - Pligavko, Catherine, Computer technology: effects on Native American communities., 2002 (Box 1)
  - Reichel, Carlyn Anne, Knee-deep: the smear campaign in modern American politics: a case study of the Swift Boat Veterans for Truth., 2005 (Box 2)
  - Schlocker, Michaela, Does spelling count? Effects of text errors in computer-mediated communication., 1999 (Box 1)
  - Stamm, Hilllary M., The decade the music died., 1998 (Box 2)
  - Wiggins, Thomas Winfield Jr., Militia speech: physiological and self-report responses to anti-government rhetoric., 1997 (Box 1)